# Amlan Banaji

Curriculum Vitae

Website: amlan-banaji.github.io

Nationality: UK

Email: afb8 "at" st-andrews.ac.uk

PhD student in Mathematics at St Andrews

# **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

I am primarily interested in the geometry and dimension theory of fractal sets and measures. I have worked extensively with fractals generated by conformal and non-conformal iterated function systems. Much of my research has focused on interpolating between different notions of dimension. I am interested in finding connections between fractal geometry and other areas of mathematics.

#### PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

- Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors (with J. M. Fraser) To appear in Transactions of the American Mathematical Society. arXiv
- Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions (with A. Rutar) Annales Fennici Mathematici 47 (2022) 939-960. arXiv
- Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence (with I. Kolossváry) Submitted. arXiv
- Generalised intermediate dimensions Submitted. arXiv

# **EDUCATION**

**University of St Andrews** 

2019–present

**PhD Mathematics** (in progress)

**Topic:** Fractal geometry and dimension theory

With the **Analysis Research Group** 

Supervisors: Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Full scholarship from the Leverhulme Trust

**University of St Andrews** 

2018-2019

**MSc Mathematics, Distinction** 

**GPA**: 19.5/20. Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

Dissertation:

Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by Professor Kenneth Falconer)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015-2018

**BA (Hons) Mathematics** 

Selected Part II courses: Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

**Thomas Tallis Sixth Form** 

2013-2015

**A-Levels:** 

 $Mathematics(A^*)$ ,  $Further Mathematics(A^*)$ ,  $Physics(A^*)$ ,  $Chemistry(A^*)$ , *History(A), Extended Project Qualification(A\*, AS level)* 

#### PRIZE

*2019*: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best taught postgraduate student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

# **TALKS**

I have given 15 talks (listed at <u>amlan-banaji.github.io/talks</u>) at conferences and seminar series including:

- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest University of Technology and Economics, June 2022)
- <u>Junior Ergodic Theory Meeting</u> (ICMS, Edinburgh (March 2022) and online (March 2021))
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, May 2022)
- <u>Dynamics and Group Geometry Early Researchers Seminar (DAGGER)</u> (Warwick, May 2022 and March 2021)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, May 2022, October 2021 and June 2020)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

• Teaching undergraduate tutorials at the University of St Andrews:

2019 – 2021: MT2502 Analysis (8 groups total) 2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- 2018 onwards: **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded **Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project** on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.
- 2017: internship at market research company Kantar TNS, working as a **data scientist** for the social media team, using Python.

### **SERVICE**

- 2022: **Referee** for *Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A* and *J. Math. Anal. Appl.*
- 2021: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.
- 2019–2021: **Treasurer** of St Andrews Mindfulness Society.

#### **MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES**

- 2022–present: London Mathematical Society
- 2020–present: Edinburgh Mathematical Society
- 2019–present: Associate Member of the <u>Institute of Mathematics and its Applications</u> (AMIMA)

# **INTERESTS AND SKILLS**

- Languages: English (native), German (conversational, A\* at GCSE), Hindi (conversational)
- **Music**: Piano (grade 8), Clarinet (toured Canada and Venice)
- **Sport:** running, badminton, chess